Contact

matt.muscas@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ matteomuscas (LinkedIn) quelluomo.github.io (Portfolio) sites.google.com/view/sebadas (Portfolio)

Top Skills

Creative Writing

figma

Adobe XD

Languages

Italian (Native or Bilingual)
English (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Create High-Fidelity Designs and Prototypes in Figma

Online Games: Literature, New Media, Narrative

Introduction to Creative Writing

Conduct UX Research and Test Early Concepts

Design a User Experience for Social Good & Prepare for Jobs

Matteo Muscas

UX Designer at Covisian

Sardinia, Italy

Summary

UX Designer with a keen eye for frontend software development and graphic design. I design accessible interactions, create low-fidelity wireframes and hi-fi prototypes and analyse user data to inform design solutions.

I also code in JavaScript and TypeScript with Stencil and Ionic using Agile and Scrum methodologies.

Experienced in managing teams. Skilled in Translation, Web Design, and Copywriting. Eager learner with a Bachelor's Degree focused in Creative Writing from Birkbeck, University of London and two full stack bootcamps at Hackademy by Aulab and OpenCampus, and Flatiron School New York.

Experience

Covisian

3 years 4 months

UX Designer

September 2022 - Present (1 year 2 months)

Cagliari, Sardinia, Italy

- · Developing comprehensive wireframes and user interfaces based on user research and identifying user needs
- · Handling user testing sessions with stakeholders to determine design changes and iterate version based on their feedback
- Implementing design updates and recommended changes based on user research and feedback to enhance UX
- Designing and conducting compelling usability testing sessions to identify user needs and improve overall user experience
- · Ensuring thorough documentation of user research and analysis to optimise user experience accordingly
- · Using Figma to create user interface elements for applications
- · Creating efficient and user-friendly designs and navigation flows

- · Using interviews and surveys to identify user requirements and improve usability
- · Collaborating with the product team to ensure optimal UX design delivery

Frontend Developer

July 2020 - July 2023 (3 years 1 month)

Cagliari, Sardinia, Italy

- Implementing web design and developing web components to build stable software using TypeScript/Javascript and StencilJS/Ionic
- Bringing mock-ups to life using HTML, SCSS, JavaScript
- Collaborating closely with the team to support projects during all phases of delivery
- Building web components that are reusable
- Rectifying front-end-related issues
- Communicating technical issues in a clear and understandable manner to the team
- Maintaining an organised workflow using GitHub
- Testing to identify bugs and technical issues
- Documenting bug reports and code changes using StoryBookJS

Savini

Graphic and Web Designer September 2018 - July 2020 (1 year 11 months) London, United Kingdom

- * Creating graphics and illustrations for marketing campaigns, menus, adverts, leaflets, business cards.
- * Preparing and handling newsletters with Mailchimp and plain HTML for 125k
- + subscribers, ensuring cross-platform and legacy devices compatibility.
- * Managing and updating Wordpress websites and their databases.
- * Revising and proofreading final print and web copies.

//SKILLS

Graphic Design / Marketing / IT / Adobe InDesign / Adobe Illustrator / Adobe Photoshop / Affinity Designer / Wordpress Development / Web Design

Rainforest Cafe

Customer Relations Manager & Floor Supervisor June 2016 - September 2018 (2 years 4 months) London, United Kingdom

* Supervision of a team of 35+ people and managing shifts with over 1500 daily guests.

- * Managing customer relations via email, phone and social media, responding to customer queries and feedback, conducting investigations over their visit, handling staff disciplinary procedures.
- * In charge of hiring new staff members, conducting interviews, handling department relations.
- * Creating and managing staff schedules.
- * Monitoring staff performances and handling assessments and appraisals
- * In charge of handling daily end of day cash and card reports and preparing reports for the accounts department.
- * Managing sales analysis and preparing sales reports.

Pole To Win UK London Localisation QA Tester October 2014 - October 2015 (1 year 1 month)

London, United Kingdom

- * Testing games across all Nintendo platforms.
- * Entering linguistic related bugs, flaws and issues into the database in a clear and concise manner.
- * Proofreading to ensure all text is accurately translated.
- * Detecting localisation and functionality bugs, and design issues.
- * Vetting bugs and mentoring new employees.
- * Providing solutions to any issues.
- * Translating between English and target language.
- * Communicate accurate information to other team members.

SKILLS//

- > Bug detection & Reporting
- > MS Office Word/Excel
- > Problem Solving
- > Organisation
- > Ability to meet deadlines and project expectations
- > Oral and written communication skills

freelance editor/writer

Freelance Writer

May 2011 - August 2014 (3 years 4 months)

- * Writing and researching accurate stories.
- * Writing features, articles, reviews and editorials.
- * Interviewing people in a range of different circumstances.
- * Seeking out and investigating stories, press releases and other media.

- * Building contacts and networking.
- * Creating and uploading visual content.

SKILLS//

- > Writing
- > Researching
- > Audio/Video Production
- > Podcasting
- > Wordpress
- > Website management

Forty-Five Square Production Designer 2014 - 2014 (less than a year)

London, United Kingdom

- * Managing IT department.
- * Setting up and managing email accounts and coworkers' cloud space.
- * Running the production schedule.
- * Creating layouts and graphics.
- * Preparing digital/printed copies.
- * Prioritising and meeting deadlines.

SKILLS//

- > Design skills
- > Basic video and photo editing
- > Logo creations
- > Running and managing websites

Rainforest Cafe Head Receptionist July 2010 - 2014 (4 years) London, United Kingdom

- * Ensuring all guests are properly greeted upon arrival and departure.
- * Providing outstanding customer service and answer queries at all times, always making sure to meet both the company's and the franchisor's high standard.
- * Ensuring that the Reception Areas are maintained in a clean, tidy and safe condition at all times.

- * Organizing the table plan in the restaurant whilst constantly liaising with the MODs in regards of events, large bookings, and dietary requirements, VIP tables.
- * To have a comprehensive knowledge of the reservation process and booking system.
- * Taking reservations and handling all type of enquiries; cross-trained as event coordinator.
- * Ensuring the Reception team is fully trained and updated through daily communication and thorough handover.
- * Coordinating the daily duties of all reception staff by assigning individual tasks, setting clear aims and objectives.
- *Cash handling and processing payments and handling cash when needed.

SKILLS

supervising up to 20 staff members / inventory control / staff training / assigning tasks and coordinating activities

Education

HACKademy by Aulab

Fullstack Software Development, Computer Programming · (2019 - 2019)

Flatiron School

Fullstack Web Development Coding Bootcamp, Computer Science · (2018 - 2019)

Birkbeck, University of London

Bachelor's Degree, Creative Writing (2010 - 2014)